Hello.
Thank you so many.
We are Gregor and Kenton,
engineer at Elastic, or at
or at least after,
we'll talk just after.
And we'll talk about
how we've crammed
plenty of GPU,
how we've trained the last generation
of models
text,
so these models
dance embedding
that are out
three weeks
now.
Yeah,
without any
so I'm
going to
we're going to
what's what we
we've done,
the models that we train,
etc.
he will explain to
how
we're
how we're
to be the
little
little secret, I'm
not going to
and I'm
I think that
we're a bit too
rarely, it's
the
how it's
we're going to
I'm
so I'm
So, who
So,
me,
we're
in the
research for the
at least,
we're
in the
member
fundate of this
but now,
we're
who
specialised in
the
management,
to the specialists,
who are
and
and we're
there are
people in
people in Europe,
and some
people who
on the
our
that
comprise
So,
a
re-ra
they're
and able to
spas
25, or TFIDF.
And we have a model that's a little marginal,
which is a reader-lm.
It's the model generative
which we,
in this moment, he is specialized in the
traduction of page HTML
in markdown.
That's a model, in fact,
it's a model that
that's a model that
will tradue
or,
more of the documents
we find on
in a form of a
more digest
for the agents
that we'll use to deploy
to everywhere.
Our actuality,
So, we
we've worked on
here a
with Gina,
now that we've
now that
the R-Ranker V3
that's out
a few months,
but,
before that,
he had not
well
we've
of Jina Embedding
V5 Text.
It's the
version text
only
of our
last model
of embedding,
which comes in
two saveur,
so I can
little model,
and a
small,
a little model,
but more
small,
it's not the
only
the same model of
we have,
we have also
the
image and the
text,
that is based on
the
VLM, that's a
model
of
vision question
answering,
you give you
give an image and a
question with
the
elements visual.
VLM and V6 are
some
So,
if you see
you see
we're
that we're
perhaps a model that
that's
the
V5 Text and
VLM1
B5 Text.
So,
thank for the
surprise,
it's
the
very
in these two
many
times,
it's
the
was ready to
and there's
a
because
it's
these
are pretty and potent
so
So,
nano, 250
million of
parameters, he
b bade of
two to three
three
three times
in terms of
terms of
parameters, it
is based on
Robert,
well that he
will more
more than I'm
I'm not
not too
I'm going to
manage these
slides.
Small, he
is a
bit more
he is based
on
I don't
I don't say
but,
but it's
the
one
million,
it's
in retrieval
classification
text similarity
clustering
on these
benchmarks
When you
to you
explain to what
what consists
the benchmark,
it's the
so we're the
very, so we're
obviously, they
are all
on the API
of Jina,
so you
can go to
you
have 10 million
of tokens
gratos,
so
make you
feel like
if you
pass
in navigation
private,
you have
10 million
of your
tokens
gratos.
He's also
also dispos
on
Ice,
so Elastic
Inference
Service,
that's
a proxy
elastic,
but for
probably,
for
playing with
with
their
models,
and that
elastic,
it's not
all
and they're
are disposed
on Hgging
Face,
so you can
go to
go and
going to
do you
know,
and test
the models
they're
in
creative commons
non-commercial
so you
can't
you can't
you
want you
want to
you
don't
know, but you
can
do you
the
R&D
on
for sure
for the
people
use the
use
the people use
the
people use
with
and
now
No,
I'm going to pass the
I'm not the paper
the paper
not
made in the
paper, and
we
don't
not
often, but
they are
related to
a
JinaVV5.
So,
so
first,
a
word
on the
the
leaderboard
and the
point that
we're
to
where is
it's
out of
collections of
datasets
who are
on
on a
leaderboard,
a leaderboard,
a
bit horrible
to
use
and
the
first is
mteb
so
only
of the
English
on
the
these little
little
datasets,
these little
bit of text
documents of
token
max
and who are
in access
liberal
with
trainset,
eval set and
all set and
problem
of this
data
is
obviously
there was
that
when the
people
were
a
problem for the
evaluation
so
there
mMMtab
that
has arrived
so
there's
the
same
principle
that's
also
again
these
little
documents
I don't
it's
not the
there's a lot
and there's a lot
of language,
it's
so it's
there's
classics,
more obscure,
like the
Swiley
or the
Korean,
where there
really very
very very
there's
there's a
certain of
the
data set
where the
evaluation
evaluation uses
the training
set.
so if there
there are
people who will
s
to
make
to do
on these
the data
data set,
have
good
is used
in the
same
the same
because it
can create
these
great
surprise.
and the
problem
with
these two
data sets,
that's
completely
open
to
everyone
and the
way
the
is declarative.
It's
we
say,
say, we
don't
use, we
have
not
used, we
using this data set in the
and
so it's a
create RTAB
so
it's
the same
principle,
so this
this
this time
these
data
are
not
available
So it
can
make
an
evaluation
that's a
little
we're a
bit more sure
that there's
not
there's not
there's
a
little
few
there's
it's a
So there
I've
have
wanted to
present a
bit,
so we
we've
did a
lot of
experience for
for
getting
and there
there's
a
lot of
little
bit of
little brick
that
can
make
that we
and I
decided
to
me
on
the
bricks
that
have
have brought
in the result
final.
So the
first brick,
it's the colon
vertebral
matricial matricial,
so we call it
the backbone
in general,
it's the point of
the point of
end up to the
So in
I don't
recommend to
person to
start to
zero,
because the
price is
a little
but the
price that
cash and
Gregor
he regruare
he will
will be
not the
one, it's
it's clearly
minimized,
but it's
what is
what is indicated
in the
paper
and it's what
And then
there's
a
complexity
that comes with
the
training of
these models,
which
demand of
the
quantities of
which are
astronomomomomics,
not
of the
order of
the
we need to
reason to
reprival or the
and the
classification.
So that's
the two
backbone that we
have
used,
so that's
the Gina
Nano,
that's
the
gina small,
and it's the
point of
our
trainingment.
A
another point
that is
very
impactant
,
and that
that will be
more than the
the choice
architecturos that you
will
you'll
able to
you're
a lot
obscure that
that you
will
branched
on your
your
it's
in fact
the
data that you
are
offer to
your
and
there,
well
obviously you
will be
a
bit
of
using
the
data
data set
public
at
a
having
good
lot
we have
not
a
one
part
a
quite
critical
is
the
in
in fact,
you have
a lot of
impact
on
it's
they're not necessarily
very
very share,
well,
you can't
it
do it
do you want to
and it's
and that
will
make a
difference
in fact.
It can
have
some
impact that
will be
honestly,
an order of
greater
to
a
little
modifications
that you
could
do you
in the
different
there
just
just for
a
bit
there
the
cleaning, filtering,
it's
will be
found
some documents that are
probably,
to find the documents
that are
proche, but
not good,
supprimed
these duplicates,
this
sort of
things,
subprime
these documents
that
they want
there are
there's, there
there's,
and the
last
step, it's a
a
little, it's a
bit a
a
piece of a
because
because in
fact,
generally the
generated of
the
data in
using the
LLM,
it's
very
it's super
much,
in
plus.
But,
in fact,
of what I've
can't see
on my
course
experience, it's
complicated to
it's quite to
do it's
and it's
quite to
see how
and it's
that way
so it's a
double
trancheant.
I think it's
very
interesting, but
it's
it's quite
we use
we use these
old LLM
and with the
little LLM
I've
not seen
the resulta
that had
sufficiently
good for
being
amelioring the
but
but even
even in doing
things
very simple.
By example,
I know
that we've
tried
to
take the query
of a
data set and just
to the
reformuling
so it's
not very
complicated,
in
saying that we
going to
gom
certain
structure
grammatical,
a bit
kind of
sort of
of
things, we
we've
a degradation
of
the model,
it's to
use
with
parsimony
and have
to have
good
metrics
to be sure
of what we
here.
I'm
here I'm a
so I'm
don't know
in the
middle in
case that
we present
not
spontaneously
It's a
what I
call the
rear
cuisine.
So the
first point,
the main
the
I've
used
for the
model
for the model
four years
and the
middle at
the time
were more
structured,
all the
used the
main
backbone
that were
Birt,
all
people
used the
same
data set
of entranment
that was
M.
Marko
and we
were, and we
compare
the
ideas of
minage,
of
the
loss
on
a,
on a
piece of
a
equality.
Today, it's
the new
new models that
are
the
backbon is different,
data sets are
different,
the
techniques
of minage are
different, so it's
very
very hard to
identify exactly the
the point
that
makes the
model
as
good that is
the
ablation study
which
are in
the
paper, but
they are
often
not complete,
so I
don't, so I
think that
this point
that,
and I
think that's
because
that's because
that
very
this point
that
makes
difficult
the
trackage
of the
points
important
or
advance
that we're
in the
other
subject
that
are a
little
are
a
little
but the
the
origin
of
training of
sometimes
a
bit enigmatic
I
think
especially
on
the
backbone
where
we
know
what has
used
and
it's
the
quantities
of
many
It's not very clear
what has been
used
in the
training
and the
we're not very
very long
to say
that we're
can't
be able to
try
on the
site
of the
data without
without
express
it's not
not
for
a design
but
the fact
that the
data
that
public
pass
at a
a moment
in a
moolinette
it's
just
very probable
and
and that
it puts
a question
on the
definition
of the
zero shot for
the
zero shot
in theory
we
the model
of retrival
has been
trained
on a pool
and there
I'm not
not a
validation
and it's
really a pool
of data
completely different
and we're
we're
on the data
on
they have
nothing to
so we're
not the
we have
really
a
data set
that
normally
of origin
completely
different.
Well,
at
the
LLLM
that
automatically
the web page
and all that,
I
don't know
at
how the
point the
zero shot
when the
most
the retrival
top
trust, the top leaderboard,
I don't
at what they've
never seen these
data
that we can
we can
questioner.
So,
after we
know that
it's not
used in
the
retrieval in
it in
but I'm
think the
definition,
it's for that
that RTAbe
exists,
at my
view,
that the
people are
conscious of that.
And then
another
thing of
the
rear
cuisine on
the leaderboard
that we
can
see on
on Gingface,
I think
there is a
there a
melange
in the
typology of
the
which are
on Sliderboard.
In fact,
these models that I
call
Unified,
that are
going generate
vectors, and
these vectors you
will use
use it
for all the
retrivol, you
will use it for
the
classif,
for
do the
retrival
asymmetric or
symetric,
that
will be the
source,
the
sole source that
you will
use.
And in
fact,
these
models there,
there will
be
there are
models that
use,
by
the
Lora adapter
,
So we
we're
that's what we have
with
Jina,
so we have
the Lora
adapter, we're
we're intercal
we'll intercaling
the
point,
we'll fris the
model
of
the model of
we're
we're just
just
train these
little
section of
this little section of
for a
special specialise
the model.
These
poe
represent a
pretty
I think
I think I
don't
I'm
think I'm
think
I'm a
of
million,
so it's
really
pretty
by
the
of the
whole.
And
and
The result
of that is when you
when you'll have
an adapter Lora
of classification and that you
will obtain
you can't
have to
have a good
result.
So you'll
have a
attention to
the type of
models that we
use for
which they
tache and the
the
manner
that we
will
plug
that on
our
elastic,
cluster elastic or
so
for the
prefix, it's
exactly the
same
thing,
it's
not
a
technology
similar,
but the
idea that
there
The problem
that
it's
the problem that
it's the same.
If you
if you
have said,
I'd
would like you
me
sort
an embedding for
for this
document for
the
classif,
the embedding that
you're
will be
not be very
very good
for the
retribol.
And that's
the
base of
a
type of
models that
are
based on
on
on Kuen,
but there
there are
other
it's a
thing
very
common.
So it's
these
technologies that
are
practical
because
that's
actually
it's
to unify
the
training when
when we
we're
doing
the clustering,
the
classive,
the retrival,
it's not simple
to jongle
with these
gradients and it's
it's a
pretty good
idea to
let it's
for that we
it's for
it's because it
can't
have
very good
performance in
each one of
some of
parasit
with one
with the
So it's
very good,
we can
be
question on
the
that
leaderboard
make all
these
models on a
piece of
while there
there
different
are a
fundamental
and I
I
repace
Okay,
Kantin.
So, how
how many
costs of these models?
Is that you
you'll
do you know about
to
you'll
I'm going to
yeah in the
co2?
Yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah,
well, okay, okay.
Uh,
well,
I'll go
by
model,
I'm going to go
with a
model Gena, and
then,
so Robert,
they're
researchers
European,
who have
trained their
models
on,
a super calculator
Bordeléleleleys, they
they've
said,
Gros, it's
it's
for five
billion, I
think that
million, in
French,
in French, is
billion,
it's
so, sorry,
the English,
for,
it's that,
$5 billion of
token.
So,
I'm
I said,
Robert,
they've
trained three
models,
one that
has
two
million of
parameters,
the
that we
have
used for
for
six
million,
one that
two
million,
two million,
So if I, if I
if I, if I
see the sum of these
models, I'm
at about about
at 2,800
million of
parameters,
the
little model,
it's
a
$7% and
$210
by all
all the
it's
linear, the
cost of
the
model,
set
andm
of
all the
hours.
And,
in fact,
it's not
not
so simple.
It's not
so simple
because
in the
two hundred
hours
they have
they've
spent
10,000
to make
R andD architectural
to
test
a
40th
of
sub-model
for
say,
that's
if you
think you
think that's
if they're
they're doing
so that's
50 million
at the
1010,000
hour
GPU, and
the cost
total, it
would have
had been 10
15,000
12,000,
15,000,
12,000.
Well,
he's
found they've
lost
three models,
I propose
propose an
amortism
to
number of
models,
I mean
I mean, I mean,
I'll divide
three, and I arrive
a 36,500
hour
GPU, plus the training,
yeah, it's that
it's a 15,000
I think I've
read at the
base, because
that,
there's more
of,
so it's
can't
not linearly
that's
quite
quadratically,
and in
gross,
I'm
getting at
42,000
GPU,
if you
would
would you
could you
want you
how cost
20,000
hour GPU,
it's at
$2 euro
at $2
it's $80K.
So it's a
bit more
than the 15K
euro
which don't
talk
in terms of
of the
energy energy
so
$1,000,
it costs
$31
megawattour.
In terms of
electricity
carbon,
Cocorico,
we're in
France,
it costs
a
bit of
uranium,
but not
a
CO2
because
we have a
mix
energy
which
emet
emet very
emmase
per per
kilowattur
per kilowattur
produced in
France.
That's
because this
this model
has been
trained in Adastra,
so that is an
hyperscaler
French,
at Bordeaux, I
think,
which has a
PUE,
so a power
usage efficiency.
It's
that is the
the infrastructure
around the
GPU is
is actually
there's
of energy to
spend in
more than the
energy that
goes in
the energy that
the
hypers
recalers
recent is
in
below of 1,
but
the
data
centers that
get
that can
go to
That's that,
I calculated,
by
taking
all that
I calculated
megawatt
which is
that's
for a
model like
that
would
we're
not
really
because it's
a
model that
is open
open source
open weight
we can
do
have
really
under
license
open
uh
it's
it's a
big
common
and
after
there's also
there's
a
thing
that's a
thing that
we
don't
not
,
here,
it's
there's a water that's
from the water
because it has
has served
to refrorode
and it's
not recaptured by the
data center,
so it's
a
not a
part in the
it's not in the
but it
will be
in the
it's a
there's a
there's
not much
in comparison to
all
for me
it's
important to
talk to
pass in a
water
a potentially
a
lot of a
,
we're at
a
the
estimations, because
because it's
due, but in
I've
put the coefficient of the
of the electricity,
reported by
EDF,
years where I've
found my
little
well,
Kuen, so
Kuen, that's
is a
made in China, they
have
been
a super
effort,
Kwan 3, it's
really,
it's
really, and it's
Kosto, but,
we're a
on a
we're at
a 306 billion tokens.
around 300,
300,000
of budget for
for Kuen 3,
I think
that's
a coqui,
but it's for Kuen3.
Well,
that's the model
is pretty,
it's the more
pretty
that's
they're the
probably that's not the
most of the time,
but in fact,
it's, in
gross, the
time of research
architectural, we're
on 200,000
hour,
GPU, but they
have
made
06 billion
to 06 billion
to, I,
don't know,
a mixture of
experts
that makes 235,
a thing like that.
So,
like,
I'm lissed,
my
little R-D
by the number
of models,
and I
I arrive at
about 26,000
R&D by
and so for
06 billion, the
model of
the model of
Jina V5
Text
Small, I'm
at 116,000
GPSU.
hour GPU,
now we're in
China, so
so we're in
China, but
we're in
a data
center
Ali,
of Alibaba,
so it's
kind of
the
high-gam
Chinese,
they say
they say that
they are
56% of
energy
renewableable.
So I
I'm
I mean at
zero, and I
count that
44% of
energy with a
mix,
with a
mean of an
amount of
carbon
that's
that I'm
found at 317
per
per kilowatt
hour.
So we're at
in
the rack
of,
oh,
that's
that's not
also.
Is that you
know,
is, is,
you know,
Yeah,
today,
we're
all
our models on
these
cards
GPU
that's
called the
H-100, which are
who are
being by
Nvidia, and at a
moment there's
a embargo
on the
market on
in China in
for not that
too too
more, I
know, I
know, there's
there was a
embargo
American,
which has
interdied the
VH00.
So
Nvidia has
sorted
from the H-8
which are
being
two different
more
more than to be two-
more expensive.
So,
the
and in
gross,
a rach
10 kilowatt
for
for 8GPU,
it's for
that I'm
that I'm at
at 10,200
divided by
8,
well,
so we're
we're pretty
pretty 25
tonne for
for an
equivalent of 25
CO2,
without
count their energy
renewable,
well,
that I
don't know
too,
75,000
litre,
it's a
little
more,
it's a
$230,000
at
pretty,
but
but that's
same
there's a
model,
there's
there
plenty of
people who
have
they're
done
and
they're
a
cost that
we
can
There's
people who train
a very
great
great model and who don't
don't
they don't
V-5 text.
So, so
I'm,
I'm, you know,
it's a
little model, we
have not, we
millions of
tokens, we're
uh, yeah,
of
uh,
yeah,
games, they are
a
, I don't know,
we have
100 times
more than, I
I think, we're
yeah,
I'd have
even
yeah,
so I'm
so,
we're at
,
we're
of the training
kind of
so I'm going to
I'm going to
see our
our billing
GCP
and back 48
hours,
48,000,
49,000,
309,
39,000, but
we have also
a cluster
in Sweden,
which is not
in GCP,
and there
we
had made a
good
10,000
hour, I
think,
so we're
at
210,000
hour
GPU,
oh,
mobile
copy-coled,
yeah,
in
all
we're at
50,000
for our
two
models,
V-5
Nano and
5 small,
reparty
on two
places
and that's
quite interesting,
so what's
what's
about about the
rac
505 million
of watt hours,
25,000 kilowatt
hour,
there's
are 43,
that's
is linear in
in
the,
power
is linear
at
the time
past
over the
time paste
by
the
intensity carbon,
we
have
99% of
the carbon
emi,
which is
for
80%
of
the time
of the
but that's
because in
the
US
U.
the mix
energetic
is more
and
more intense
in
carbon
than
in
suede
water,
and for
an
addition
for an
$200,000
and I
think,
we're
see
completely
because
we
launch
many
experience
in
parallel
like
there
has a
multiplication
of their
and
of their, and
and certainly a complexification
of the traceability
of the effectiveness,
it's a
time,
it's a time,
it's a
but we're
not the
work
that's
really,
we're
pushing a
course plus,
then the other
course
in the
time and then it
work
and then we
need to
re-ence
four experience
for
the Ablation
study and
say,
it was that
it
worked, and
and
actually, and
it's
very
very hard,
I'm not
person
and I'm
very hard,
it's
very
Well,
they're more
more organized
than me,
but Robert, it's
that,
on 21
researchers on
it's applied,
it's
there's
and this dip
between an
amount of
a 10,
15,000
hour
GPU, and
more the
50,000
that I
measureed,
I
would say
I'd
more than
the 10,000
than
than the
50,000,
because
all
the
experiences
don't
not
finish
in the
model.
I'm
the
question of
real
impact
of what
is
in the
article.
All right,
the apparel.
So what we
can understand
for me,
is that the open
source,
the open
weight,
is very essential,
we create
these common,
that we
re-rans to
the models
like Robert
and Coen-3,
it's like a
a
per rote for
our
imaginerer fertile,
it's a
a bit an
economy of
finally.
It's a
very difficult
to
estimates the
cost,
even more
in intern,
having access to
the
accounts,
Google and
I've
had to
allerer
to
able to
this resource
to tell
the experience
that's
going to
get in the
model,
because we
train four
family
of models
all the
time in
at the
time in the
time, we're
we're not
imagine
many times
more
and the
people
people who
don't
give to
that for me
for me,
it's an
impas
on all
all the
all the plans,
so the
models,
it's the
well,
yes,
oh,
thanks.
Thank you.